Inventaris van de digitale duplicaten van de lokale bestuursarchieven van de Nederlandse koloniën Essequibo, Demarara en Berbice en notariële akten [tezamen ‘Dutch Series’ genoemd], aanwezig in de National Archives of Guyana te Georgetown, (1685) 1720-1814 (1827)
Nationaal Archief, Den Haag
- DEMARARA, 2.
  - C Demarara: Court of Civil Justice, 2.2.
    - `Shipbonds´, Affadavits from plantation owners on the debts etc. that were possibly made by their contracted ship captains, 1811; AZ.1.29; 1 Cover
    - List of owners of plantations., 1774; AZ.1.76; 1 Cover
    - Account book on clothing in the company’s warehouse, 1802 - 1803; AZ.1.40A; 1 Cover
  - B Demarara: Court of Criminal Justice, 2.3.
    - Interrogations (Examinations)., 1793 - 1808; AZ.1.55, AB.3.52B; 2 Covers
      - June 1793 - June 1794, AB.3.52B
      - 1795, 1797, 1806 – 1808, AZ.1.55
- ESSEQUIBO & DEMARARA, 3.
  - A Essequibo & Demarara: Combined Council (Court of Policy & Civil Justice), 3.1.
    - Miscellaneous minutes on proceedings, 1774 - 1812; AZ.1.42, AB.3.42A-AB.3.52A; 13 Covers
      - January 1774 - February 1776, AB.3.42A
      - January 1774 - February 1776, AB.3.42B
      - January 1778 - October 1778, AB.3.43
      - July 1789 - November 1789, AB.3.44
      - April 1790 - June 1790, AB.3.45
      - June 1790 - December 1790, AB.3.46
      - January 1791 - May 1791, AB.3.47
      - June 1791 - December 1791, AB.3.48
      - January 1792 - May 1792, AB.3.49
      - May 1792 - December 1792, AB.3.50
      - January 1793 - July 1793, AB.3.51
      - July 1793 - October 1793, AB.3.52A
      - 1777,1789,1792,1795,1797,1799,1800,1803 - 1804,1805 - 1806,1807,1808,1810,1811,1812, Contains Excerpts, AZ.1.42
    - Index to the minutes, 1773, 1776 - 1779; AB.1.379A; 1 Cover
    - Miscellaneous attachments to the minutes, 1706 – 1811; AZ.1.41-AZ.1.60; 4 Covers.
      - Register 1759 - 1773, 1776 – 1781, Includes notary acts, AZ.1.41
      - 1706, 1750, 1790, 1787, 1789, 1786, 1784, 1784, 1781, 1777, 1775, 1767, 1769, 1761, 1811.1783, AZ.1.43
      - 1761, 1767, 1769,1775, 1781, 1784,1787 – 1796, Includes undated 18th century material, AZ.1.60
      - 1790 - 1797, AZ.1.44
    - Financial documents related to the minutes, 1782 – 1793; AZ.1.48-AZ.1.49; 2 Covers.
      - 1782 - 1790, AZ.1.48
      - 1791 - 1793, AZ.1.49
    - Account book on the estate of deceased owners of plantations, 1789 - 1791; AZ.1.30; 1 Cover
    - Account book containing receipts and expenditures of the government, 1794; AZ.1.88; 1 Cover
    - Capital Account register, 1803 - 1809; AZ.1.19; 1 Cover
    - Account book estate (incomplete), 1812 - 1813; AZ.1.64; 1 Cover
      Contains index
    - loose page of register mortgages., 1785 – 1791; AZ.1.65; 1 Page
    - Account book Marshals Office, 1813 - 1815; AZ.1.66; 1 Cover
    - Inventory of the records of the Courts of Policy and Civil Justice in Essequibo and Demerara, 1790; AZ.1.85; 1 Cover
    - Acts on land registry., 1792 - 1802; AZ.1.87; 1 Cover
    - Policy plan for new administration of colonies (draft), 1796; AZ.1.70; 1 Cover
    - Cargo lists (‘Bills of lading’) of incoming & out - going ships., 1774, 1775; AZ.1.72; 1 Cover
    - Travel passes, 1774, 1775; AZ.1.71; 1 Cover
  - B Essequibo & Demarara: Court of Policy, 3.2.
    - Miscellaneous minutes of proceedings & Attachments, 1794 – 1814; div.nrs.; 34 Covers
      Minutes from August 1807 in English
      - January 1794 - June 1794, AB.3.53
      - July 1794 - November 1794, AB.3.54
      - January 1795, AB.3.55
      - April 1795 - May 1795, AB.3.57
      - May 1795, AB.3.58
      - May 1795 - June 1795, AB.3.59
      - July 1795 - September 1795, AB.3.60
      - October 1795 - January 1796, AB.3.61
      - January 1796 - May 1796, AB.3.62
      - 30 Jan 1797 - 15 Sep 1797, AB.1.1
      - January 1798 – October 1800, AB.1.2
      - June 1796 - November 1796, AB.3.63
      - January 1799 - November 1799, AB.3.64
      - January 1800 - November 1800, AB.3.65
      - January 1801 - December 1802, AB.3.66
      - December 1802 - April 1803, AB.3.67
      - April 1803 - September 1803, AB.3.68
      - February 1803, Contains excerpts, AZ.1.40C
      - September 1803 - July 1804, AB.3.69
      - November 1804 – August 1805, AB.3.70
      - September 1803 – August 1804, AB.1.5
      - August 1804 – November 1805, AB.1.6
      - January 1806 - November 1806, AB.3.71
      - February 1807 - December 1807, AB.3.72
      - January 1808 – May 1807, Contains printed incoming letters, AB.1.7
      - January – December 1808, AB.1.8
      - January - November 1809, AB.1.9
      - January – December 1810, AB.1.10
      - January – December 1811, AB.1.12
      - January – April 1812, AB.1.13
      - April - August 1812, AB.1.14
      - September - November 1812, AB.1.15
      - January - August 1813, AB.1.16
      - October 1813 - November 1814, AB.1.17
    - Index to the minutes., 1808 - 1814; AB.1.397B; 1 Cover
    - Attachments related to the minutes, 1798 - 1814; AZ.1.45-AZ.1.47; 3 Covers
      - 1798 - 1805, AZ.1.45
      - 1806 - 1807, AZ.1.46
      - 1808 – 1814, AZ.1.47
    - Financial documents related to the minutes, 1793 - 1814; AZ.1.40-AZ.1.50; 4 Covers
      - 1793 - 1802, AZ.1.48
      - 1801 - 1814, AZ.1.40
      - 1803 - 1814, AZ.1.50
      - 1801 – 1814, Also contains undated material, AZ.1.40B
    - Miscellaneous letters and instructions from the States General and/or Stadholder of the Dutch Republic, 1747 - 1792; AG.2.1-AG.2.8; 4 Covers
      - 1747 - 1773 Marked: A, AG.2.1
      - 1773 - 1776 Marked: B, AG.2.3
      - 1776 - 1778 Marked: C, AG.2.4
      - 1790 – 1792 ‘ Duplicates & triplicates’, contains parchment pages, AG.2.8
    - Miscellaneous general letters (incoming & outgoing), 1792 - 1821; AO.1.1A, AC.2.1-AC.3.4A; 7 Covers
      - 1792 – 1797, Contains copied Petitions, AO.1.1A
      - 1799 – 1807, Contains despatches to the Secretary of State (incoming), AC.2.1
      - 1804 – 1809, Contains despatches from the Secretary of State (outgoing), Contains Index, AC.3.1
      - January 1812 - January 1816, AC.2.3
      - January 1812 - March 1822, AC.3.2
      - 1813, AC.3.3
      - 1813 – 1821 Contains Index, AC.3.4A
    - Miscellaneous Petitions to the Director - General, 1782 - 1814; AO.1.1A-AZ.1.69; 7 Covers
      - 1782, 1789, 1794,1795, 1796, AZ.1.69
      - 1789, 1792, 1793,1795, 1797, 1799 Contains undated material, AZ.1.51
      - 1792 – 1797 Contains letters, AO.1.1A
      - 1800 - 1805, AZ.1.52
      - 1806 - 1808, 1810, AZ.1.53
      - 1811 - 1812, AZ.1.54
      - 1813 – 1814 Contains Index, AO.1.1B
    - Miscellaneous publications of the Dutch west India company (Proclamations, Ordinances Instructions etc.)., 1681 - 1804; div.nrs.; 11 Covers
      - 1735 – 1804, Also regards Berbice; includes list of freed slaves 1765, AZ.1.20
      - Forms of oath & prayer at meetings, English translation of ‘Plan to redres’, AG.2.5; 1777 – 1796, Contains Register
      - 1765 - 1773, AG.1.2B
      - 1788 - 1796, AZ.1.3C
      - 1790 - 1792, AZ.1.3A
      - 1795, AC.10.1B
      - 1796 - 1802, AZ.1.3B
      - 1803 – 1804, Contains index, AZ.1.90
      - 1793 Concerns: Willem Augustus baron Grovestins who became governor in 1793, AZ.1.63
      - After 1795; Form of oath of civil servants, AZ.1.56
  - Essequibo & Demarara: Court of Civil Justice, 3.3.
    - Miscellaneous minutes of the Proceedings, 1745 - 1749, 1812 - 1814; AZ.1.86, AB.3.75; 2 Covers
      - July 1745 - February 1749, AB.3.75
      - November 1812 - February1814, AZ.1.86
    - Attachments related to the minutes., 1788 - 1796; AZ.1.60; 1 Cover
    - Miscellaneous protocols with acts of transfer of properties, goods and attachments, 1706, 1767 – 1813; AZ.3.1-AZ.3.9; 15 Covers
      Series continues in British period from 1815
      - 1767 - 1777, AZ.3.1
      - 1778 - 1785, AZ.3.2
      - 1786 - 1792, AZ.3.3
      - 1793 - 1795, AZ.3.5
      - 1794 - 1796, AZ.3.6
      - 1792 - 1793, AZ.3.7
      - 1797, AZ.3.8
      - 1798 - 1800, AZ.3.9
      - 1801 - 1802, AZ.3.10
      - 1803, AZ.3.11
      - 1804, AZ.3.12
      - 1805 - 1807, AZ.3.13
      - 1808 - 1809, AZ.3.14
      - 1810 - 1813, AZ.3.15
      - 1815, AZ.3.16
    - Miscellaneous registers on mortgages, 1811 - 1814; AZ.4.31-AZ.4.32; 2 Covers
      - 1811 - 1813, AZ.4.31
      - 1814, AZ.4.32
    - Miscellaneous registers on the applications to marriage, 1758 - 1816; AZ.9.1-AZ.9.4; 4 Covers
      Contains Indexes and Attachments
      - 1758, 1760 - 1766, 1769, 1772, 1775 - 1778, 1780 - 1789, AZ.9.1
      - 1789, 1793 - 1799, AZ.9.2
      - 1799 - 1806, Contains acts on Berbice, 1799, AZ.9.3
      - 1814 – 1816, AZ.9.4
    - Miscellaneous protocols, deeds (notary acts), 1756 - 1781; AZ.1.41 -AZ.1.41B; 3 Covers
      Also referring to Court of Civil Justice
      - 1756 - 1775, AZ.1.41B
      - 1776 – 1781, AZ.1.41
      - 1759 - 28 July 1773, AZ.1.41A
- SOCIETY OF BERBICE & SUCCESORS, 4.
  - A Berbice: Court of Policy & Court of Criminal Justice, 4.1.
    - Miscellaneous minutes of proceedings, 1755 - 1814; div.nrs.; 19 Covers
      - 1755 - 1763, AB.3.77
      - 1766 - 1776, AB.3.78
      - 1774 - 1781, AB.3.79
      - 1774 - 1783, AB.3.80
      - 1780 – 1795, Contains Excerpts and Index on the years 1720 - 1795, AZ.1.38
      - 1781 - 1790, AB.3.83
      - 1790 - 1793, AB.3.84
      - 1799, Contains Index, AZ.1.31B
      - 1799 - 1801, AB.3.89A
      - 1801 - 1802, AB.3.91
      - 1802 - 1803, AZ.1.31A
      - 1802 – 1803, Contains Index and Attachments, AB.3.92
      - 1803 - 1806, AB.3.93
      - 1805 - 1806, AB.3.94
      - 1806 – 1808, Contains Index, AB.3.99
      - 1809 - 1810, AB.6.1B
      - 1809 – 1810, AZ.1.23
      - 1810 - 1814, AB.1.11
      - 1812 – 1814, AB.6.40A
    - Miscellaneous Interrogations (Examinations), 1782 - 1814; AZ.1.36-AZ.1.5, AB.3.82; 3 Covers
      - 1782, AB.3.82
      - 1799 - 1809, AZ.1.36
      - 1814, AZ.1.5
    - Attachments to the minutes, 1807 - 1809; AB.3.89B; 1 Cover
    - Miscellaneous Letters and Letter books, 1747-1817; div.nrs.; 12 Covers
      For Despatches (incoming/outgoing) 1804 - 1814 see Combined Council Essequibo & Demerara
      - 1747 - 1755, AG.1.1
      - 1781 - 1804, AZ.1.4
      - 1793 – 1796, Also contains Petitions, AB.3.85
      - 1796 – 1806, Also contains Petitions, AB.3.87
      - 1805 - 1810, AZ.1.13
      - 1812, AB.6.1D
      - 1812, AB.6.2
      - 1811 – 1812, Contains Index, AB.6.3A
      - 1814, Not in chronological order, AB.6.3B
      - 1814, AB.6.3C
      - 1814 - 1815, AB.6.4A
      - 1814 – 1817, AZ.1.12
    - Miscellaneous Petitions, 1764-1812; div.nrs.; 8 Covers
      - 1764 - 1778, AZ.1.6
      - 1765 - 1804, AZ.1.15
      - 1778.1792, AB.3.81
      - 1806 - 1807, AB.3.98
      - 1806 – 1809, Contains Index, AB.3.100
      - 1809 – 1812, Contains Index, AB.6.37
      - 1811, AZ.1.89
      - 1812, AB.6.39B
    - Miscellaneous Notifications, Publications, Proclamations, Ordinances, Government notices, Instructions, 1685-1819; div.nrs.; 13 Covers
      - 1685 - 1716, 1782 - 1796, AC 10.1A
      - 1734 – 1756, Contains Index, AZ.1.8
      - 1735 – 1804, Also concerns Essequibo & Demerara, Includes. list of freed slaves 1765, AZ.1.20
      - Instructions civil servants 1737 - 1775, AZ.1.21A
      - 1740 - 1763, AZ.1.7
      - 1741 – 1793, Contains Index, AI 2.1A
      - Notifications (register) 1741 – 1818, Partly English translation of AI 2.1A, AI 2.1B
      - Ordinances etc. 1783,.Partly in French, AZ.1.2B
      - Notifications 1794 - 1819, AZ.1.34
      - Notifications, Ordinances etc. 1796 – 1798,. Contains register, AB.3.88
      - Publications 1800 – 1804,. Contains Index, AB.3.90
      - Ordinances etc. 1802 – 1803,Contains Index, AZ.1.2A
      - Notifications 1804 – 1813, Contains Index, AZ.1.37
    - Miscellaneous notifications on the estates of deceased persons or persons soon to leave, 1767 -1810; AZ.1.10-AZ.1.9; 5 Covers
      - 1767-1788, AZ.1.35
      - 1755-1805. Contains index, AZ.1.35A
      - 1788-1797, AZ.1.9
      - 1797-1810, AZ.1.10
      - 1799-1806, AZ.1.58
  - B Berbice: Court of Civil Justice, 4.2.
    - Minutes of proceedings, 1749 – 1808; AZ.1.59, AB.3.2-AB.3.99; 6 Covers
      - 1749 - 1751, AB.3.76
      - 1757 - 1765, AB.3.2
      - 1788 - 1789, AZ.1.59
      - 1794 - 1796, AB.3.86
      - 1806 - 1807, AB.3.97
      - 1806 – 1808, Also concerns Criminal Justice, AB.3.99
    - Attachments tot the Minutes, 1804-1806; AB.3.95-AB.3.96; 2 Covers
      - 1804, AB.3.96
      - 1805 – 1806, AB.3.95
    - Death register, 1766 - 1798; AL.2.1A; 1 Cover
    - Miscellaneous protocols with notary acts, Contains Indexes (incomplete), 1762 – 1814; AZ.1.22-AZ.1.33, AC.9.1A-AC.9.9; 81 Covers
      Notary overview
      1762 - 1765 E.F. Harkenroth
      1765 - 1770 Hendrik Noppen
      1771 - 1779 Hendrik Noppen, Laurens Wybrand Beth, M. Londonck
      1776 - 1782 Laurens Wybrand Beth
      1781 - 1789 Laurens Wybrand Beth, Jacobus Broekhuijsen
      1783 - 1789 Jacobus Broekhuijsen
      1790 - 1794 Laurens Wybrand Beth
      1795 Paulus Eggers, Barend Lohman
      1796 - 1805 Paulus Eggers
      1805 - 1807 Jacob.Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk
      1808 - 1810 Jan Jacob van der Stoop
      1810 - 1814 Richard Clark Downer
      - 1762 – 1765, Notary: E.F. Harkenroth, AC.9.1A
      - Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.1B
      - 1765 – 1766, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AZ.1.27
      - 1765 – 1769, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.1C
      - 1766, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AZ.1.32
      - 1768 – 1769, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.2
      - 1769 – 1770, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.3
      - 1770 – 1771, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.4
      - 1771 – 1772, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.5
      - 1771 – 1779, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, L.W. Beth, M. Londonck, AC.9.6
      - 1772 – 1773, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.7
      - 1771 – 1778, Notary: Hendrik Noppen, AC.9.8A
      - 1776 – 1777, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.8B
      - 1778 – 1780, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.9
      - 1779 – 1782, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.10
      - 1781 – 1789, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.11
      - 1783 – 1784, Notary:Jacobus Broekhuijsen, AZ.1.33
      - 1785 – 1786, Notary:Jacobus Broekhuijsen, AC.9.12
      - 1787 – 1788, Notary:Jacobus Broekhuijsen, AC.9.13A
      - 1789, Notary:Jacobus Broekhuijsen, AC.9.13B
      - 1790 – 1791, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.14
      - 1790 – 1798, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.15
      - 1792 – 1793, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AZ.1.22
      - 1793 – 1794, Notary: Laurens Wybrand Beth, AC.9.16
      - 1795, Notary: Paulus Eggers, Barend Lohman, AC.9.17
      - 1796, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.18
      - 1797, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.19
      - 1797 – 1799, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.20
      - 1798, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.21
      - 1799, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.22
      - 1799 – 1804, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.23
      - 1800, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.24
      - 1800 – 1801, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.25
      - 1801, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.27
      - 1801, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.26
      - 1802, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.28
      - 1802, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.29
      - 1802, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.30
      - 1803, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.31
      - 1803, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.32
      - 1803, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.33
      - 1804, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.34
      - 1804, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.35
      - 1804, Notary: Paulus Eggers, AC.9.36
      - 1804 – 1805, Notary: Paulus Eggers, Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.37
      - 1805, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.38
      - 1804 – 1805, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.39
      - 1805, Notary:Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.40
      - 1805, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.41
      - 1806, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.42
      - 1806, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.43
      - 1806, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.44
      - 1806, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.45
      - 1807, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.46
      - 1807, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.47
      - 1807, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.48
      - 1807, Notary: Jacob Gerard Cloot de Nieuwerkerk, AC.9.49
      - 1808, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.50
      - 1808, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.52
      - 1808, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.53
      - 1809, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.54
      - 1809 – 1811, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.55
      - 1810, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.56
      - 1810, Notary: Jan Jacob van der Stoop, AC.9.57A
      - 1810, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.57B
      - 1811, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.58
      - 1811, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.59
      - 1811, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.60
      - 1812, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.61
      - 1812, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.62
      - 1812, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.63
      - 1812, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.64
      - 1812, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.66
      - 1812 – 1814, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.65
      - 1813, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.67
      - 1813, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.68
      - 1814, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.69
      - 1814, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.70
      - 1814, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.71
      - 1814, Notary: Richard Clark Downer, AC.9.72
    - Miscellaneous protocols with acts of transfer (or transport) of properties, goods etc., 1770 - 1814; AZ.3.205-AZ.3.212; 8 Covers
      This series was renumbered after 2013, see Attachment C.2 for reference to old inventory numbers. Also contains Attachments.
      - 1770 - 1779, AZ.3.205
      - 1780 - 1790, AZ.3.206
      - 1795 - 1798, AZ.3.207
      - 1798 - 1800, AZ.3.208
      - 1800 - 1802, AZ.3.209
      - 1802 - 1804, AZ.3.210
      - 1809 - 1812, AZ.3.211
      - 1812 – 1814, AZ.3.212
    - Miscellaneous registers on mortgages, 1737 - 1812; AZ.4.137-AZ.4.145; 9 Covers
      This Series was renumbered after 2013, see Attachment C.2 for reference to old inventory numbers
      - 1737 – 1763 Contains Index, AZ.4.137
      - 1765 - 1770, AZ.4.138
      - 1770 - 1773, AZ.4.139
      - 1773 - 1776, AZ.4.140
      - 1777 - 1789, AZ.4.141
      - 1789 - 1797, AZ.4.142
      - 1800 - 1805, AZ.4.143
      - 1805 - 1809, AZ.4.144
      - 1810 – 1812, AZ.4.145
    - Registers of Miscellaneous Deeds, 1810 - 1813; AZ.1.57, AZ.7.56-AZ.7.57; 3 Covers
      See also AZ.7.5
      - 1767 - 1800, AZ.1.57
      - 1810 - 1813, AZ.7.56
      - 1814 – 1821, AZ.7.57
    - Register on the establishment of power of attorney., 1800 - 1813; AZ.8.50; 1 Cover
      This Inventory number was renumbered after 2013, see Attachment C.2 for reference to old number
    - Register on a variety of legal actions., 1800 - 1804; AZ.7.5; 1 Cover
  - C Berbice: Court of Policy & Court of Civil Justice, 4.3.
    - Protocol on the concessions of land, including the necessary surveys., 1738 - 1802; AZ.1.28; 1 Cover
    - Conditions on the selling of slaves., 1764 - 1784; AZ.1.26-AZ.1.32A; 2 Covers
      - 1764 - 1772, AZ.1.26
      - 1773 – 1784, AZ.1.32A
    - Account book on the estates of deceased owners in regard to the administration for orphans., 1789 - 1791; AZ.1.30; 1 Cover
    - Register with instructions for the military and musterrolls of soldiers, Contains Index., 1802 - 1804; AZ.1.39; 1 Cover
- NEWSPAPERS, 5.
  - Miscellaneous issues of the Essequibo & Demerara Royal Gazette, 1803 – 1815; div.nrs.; 7 Covers
    - October 1803 - December 1805. Nrs. 40 - 157, AH.1
    - January 1811 - December 1811. Vol VI nrs. 339 - 437, AH.2A
    - unknown, AH.2B
    - January 1812 - December 1812. Vol VII nrs. 444 - 535, AH.3A
    - unknown, AH.3B
    - January 1813 - December 1813. Vol VII nrs. 724 - 826, AH.4
    - January 1815 - December 1815. Nrs. 752 - 854, AH.6
    - The Berbice Gazette, Nrs. 438 - 575. February 1813 - September 1815., AH.5; 1 Cover